SMITH KAMLESH GAJJAR

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

<u>V +91-9820554494</u> smith.gajjar@gmail.com https://www.smithgajjar.dev smithg09 smithg09 hlogs.smithgajjar.dev

Senior Full Stack Developer and Solutions Architect with over 2.9 years of experience in startups, building applications and open source projects using several languages and JavaScript frameworks, managing and optimizing backend infrastructure including deployment, scalability, performance and 3rd party service integrations.

EXPERIENCE

Tekie Senior Full Stack Developer

June 2022 – Present

Remote

Full Stack Developer

June 2021 – June 2022

Feb 2021 – June 2021

Frontend Developer Intern

- Tekie is a B2B Ed-tech platform that uses storytelling to make learning to code a movie-like experience. As a core team member collaborated and scaled platform to over **500+ schools**.
- Developed user facing modules, a PWA based on **Reactjs** and **Redux** and a Desktop App using **Electron.js**. Optimized Landing Page Score/Performance and SEO to **99%** to improve visibility and **Core Web Vitals**.
- Developed, Managed and Optimized API and backend architecture for enhanced scalability and performance, reducing response time by over **60**% utilizing **Node.js**, **GraphQL**, **MongoDB**, **Redis** and CDN Caching.
- Developed and Managed Internal Reports and tooling architecture for Business Team utilizing Node.js, **ETL Process** (From MongoDB to SQL), **PostgreSQL** and **Python** (Flask) for data-driven decisions.
- Integrated different 3rd party services such as **GSuit**, **Newrelic**, **Sentry**, **Elastic Search**, **Stellate** (GraphQL Caching) and **GA/GTM/Looker Studio** to improve and monitor application performance.
- Managed and Optimized DevOps infrastructure and Configured CI/CD on Github/Jenkins based of Kubernetes, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Azure Services and AWS Services such as EC2, EKS, ECR, S3, Elastic Transcoder and CloudFront.
- Developed and Contributed to open-source NPM libraries for the platform, mongodb-aggregation-builder, tekie-content-editor, react-blockly-playground. Developed and Led many Proof of Concept's for Product Development.
- Interacting and engaging in discussions with stakeholders from various departments to determine and deliver optimal tech solutions aligned with business requirements.
- Mentored, Guided and led a team of 7 in spearheading the product development and seamless **migration** of an product suite. Encouraged code hygiene and best practices while building along with peer code reviews.

InVideo 🔀 Mumbai

Front-end Developer Intern

- InVideo is an best rated online professional video editing SaaS Platform with over 7M+ users.
- Built new user facing modules by converting designs from Sketch and InVision into pixel-perfect and responsive screens using **Angular** 7, HTML, SCSS and **TypeScript**.
- Helped in fixing cross-browser inconsistencies in the interface using **BrowserStack**.

PROJECTS

Lookahead 🗗

- Look ahead (fetch) Apollo GraphQL fields with recursive joins (\$lookup) in a single MongoDB Aggregation Query. mongodb-aggregation-builder 🗷
 - Building MongoDB Aggregation Pipeline in an easier and more readable way built using Typescript.

GraphQL Nodejs Backend Starter

• A Typesafe NodeJS Backend Server Boilerplate/Starter Built using Typescript/MongoDB/GraphQL/Redis.

react-blockly-playground NPM 🗗

• A React Wrapper for using Blockly, the visual programming editor from Google Blockly.

View all projects () smithg09

June 2019 - July 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks: JavaScript, Python, SQL, NoSQL, NodeJS, GraphQL, ReactJS, Angular, TypeScript, Redis, NGINX, Electron, HTML, CSS/Sass, React Native., Next.js, Redux. Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

Tools: AWS, Azure, Sentry, Jenkins, Git, Webpack, Notion, Vercel, Docker, Jest, Jira, Trello, Looker Studio, GA/GTM

EDUCATION

Vivekanand Educational Society's Institute of Technology

2018 - 2021

Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer Science

Mumbai, Maharashtra

K.J.Somaiva Polytechnic

2015 – 2018

Diploma In Computer Engineering

Mumbai, Maharashtra